firs.gov.ng 2016-06-16

# Privacy Policy Statement

**PRIVACY POLICY STATEMENT**

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) is a government agency established to collect tax and therefore, to do so, gathers information in a variety of ways in other to discharge her responsibilities as provided by the Federal Inland Revenue Service Establishment Act, 2007.

**Personal Information Collection**

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) collects and uses your personal information for the purposes for which it is relevant to fulfilling the obligations of the Service as a tax collection agency established by the government of the Federal Republic of Nigeria. The Service collects information that you provide for the purpose of registering with the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) as a taxpayer and other information that you may provide due to some transactions you may carry out over this website. We may also gather information that you provide for the purpose of subscribing to the website services; and any other information that you may send to the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) for any purpose or any information the Service may gather from other government agencies or any other sources for the purposes of carrying out her duties as provided under the Federal Inland Revenue Service Act, 2007.

**Using Personal Information**

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) may use your personal information to:

       i.        administer this website;

       ii.       personalize the website for you;

      iii.       enable your access to and use of the website services;

      iv.       publish information about you on the website;

      v.        send to you statements and invoices; 

      vi.       collect payments from you; and

      vii.      for any other purpose that the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) deems fit to do so.

Where the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) discloses your personal information to its agents or sub-contractors for these purposes, the agent or sub-contractor in question will be obligated to use that personal information in accordance with the terms of this privacy statement.

In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere above, the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) may disclose your personal information to the extent that it is required to do so by law, in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, and in order to establish, exercise or defend its legal rights, including but not limited to providing information to others for the purpose of prevention of fraud or other criminal offences.

**Securing Your Data**

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) will take reasonable technical and organisational precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. 

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) will store all the personal information you provide on its secure servers.

Information relating to electronic transactions entered into via this website will be protected by encryption technology.

**Cross-border Data Transfers**

Information that the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) collects may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) operates to enable the use of the information in accordance with this privacy policy.

In addition, personal information that you submit for publication on the website will be published on the internet and may be available around the world.

You agree to such cross-border transfers of personal information.

**Updating This Statement**

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) may update this privacy policy by posting a new version on this website.

You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are familiar with any changes. In the event that any information we have of you on the website is found to be incorrect in any material form, it is primarily incumbent upon you to so notify the Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) and demand correction or updating of same.

**Other Websites**

This website contains links to other websites.

The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS) is not responsible for the privacy policies or practices of any third party.

Contact:  The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS), No. 20 Sokode Crescent, Wuse Zone 5, Abuja.

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS)’s treatment of your personal information, please write to:

By email to: oec@firs.gov.ng; or

By post to: The Federal Inland Revenue Service (FIRS), No. 20 Sokode Crescent, Wuse Zone 5, Abuja.
